A Guide to the Robert S. Bloxom Papers, 1978-2003
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Robert S. Bloxom Papers, 1978-2003
The Library of Virginia
40987
36.2 cubic feet (79 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Robert S. Bloxom, Mappsville.
Biographical Information
Robert S. Bloxom was born in Baltimore, Maryland on 26 April 1937. He is the son of Brantley S. Bloxom and Nancy Miles. He attended Fork Union Military Academy, where he was valedictorian and batallion commander. He then attended the University of Richmond and graduated in 1959. He married Patricia Killmon. Bloxom is a resident of Accomack County on Virignia's Eastern Shore, where he owned and operated Bloxom Auto Supply in Mappsville. He was elected to the Virginia House of Delegates, and represented the 100th District from 1978 until he resigned in 2003. Bloxom was a member of numerous committees, including Agriculture, Appropriations, Finance, and Rules. He also served on various boards and commissions, including the Chesapeake Bay Commission, Chesapeake Bay Partnership Council, and the Jamestown-Yorktown Foundation. Following his retirement from the Virginia General Assembly, Bloxom served as Secretary of Agriculture and Forestry in the admininistrations of Governors Timothy M. Kaine and Mark R. Warner.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1978-2003, of Robert S. Bloxom (b. 1937) of Mappsville, Accomack County, Virginia, who represented the 100th District in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1978 to 2003. Includes legislative files, issue files, agency files, county files, and reports and publications.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Legislative Files.
II. Issue Files.
III. Agency Files.
IV. County Files.
V. Reports and Publications.
Contents List
- Series I. Legislative Files, 1978-2003., Extent: 17 boxes. (Box 1-17)
  The legislative files include drafts and final copies of bills and resolutions introduced by Bloxom, correspondence with constituents, fellow legislators, advocacy groups, and government officials, background materials, clippings, notes, memoranda, summaries, legal opinions, roll call votes, and impact statements. There are also patron reports generated by the House Clerk which give summmaries, dates, and actions taken by the General Assemby on legislation introduced by Bloxom. Areas of interest reflected in the legislation he introduced include aquaculture, the Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel, Chesapeake Bay preservation, crab scraping, pots, and traps, farmers' markets, land management, local taxes and fees, oyster and clam dredging, tax exemptions for non-profit organizations, town charters, wetlands, and youth and gang violence. There is also a large amount of material concerning redistricting in Virginia in 1981, 1991, and 2001, as well as records of the House Appropriations Committee.
  Arranged chronologically by year.
  - 1978
    - Bills Introduced. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - School Bus Toll (H.J.R. 118). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1979
    - Legislation. (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - 1980
    - Bills Introduced. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Legislation. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1981
    - Bills. (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Redistricting. (Box 1, Folder 9-13)
    - Redistricting. (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - 1982
    - Agriculture Bills. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Alternate Forms of Government (H.B. 15 and 61). (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Assorted Legislation. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Cemetery Study Committee (H.J.R. 139) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Chesapeake Bay Legislation. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - DUI Bills. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Fishing Management Area C (H.B. 479). (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Judicial Interview Panel. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Queen Sound Landing - Judge (H.B. 391). (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
    - Taxes and Appropriations. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1983
    - Amusement Machine Operators Tax. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Bills. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Chincoteague 75th Anniversary. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Containerized Cargo (H.B. 136). (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Crab Scrapes and Dredges (H.B. 131). (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Crab Scraping Time Limits. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Francis Makemie Day. (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - License Exemption - Salt Water Sport Vehicles (H.B. 134) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Non-Resident Trapping Licenses (H.B. 586). (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Registration for Land Surveyors, etc. (H.B. 231). (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Special Permits for Trucks Hauling Virginia-Grown Farm Produce (H.B. 133). (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Surf Clam Harvesting. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Taking Certain Streets Into Secondary System of Highways (H.B. 137). (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Truck Weights (H.B. 133). (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1984
    - Bills. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Cannon Easement - Middlesex (H.B. 592). (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Coal Transportation Costs (H.B. 722). (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Death of Blackstone Drummond Ayres. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Eastern Shore Community Development Group Tax Exemption (H.B. 281). (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Middlesex Resolution (H.B. 140). (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Registration Fees and Weights for Tow Trucks. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Saxis. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - State Leave Policy (H.B. 139). (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Taking Streets Into the Secondary Highway System (H.B. 143). (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Tangible Personal Property Tax (H.B. 1086). (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1985
    - Crab Pots (H.B. 1144). (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Name Change (H.B. 1455). (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Relief of J. Dennis Fox (H.B. 1085). (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Retaining Crabs When Oyster Dredging (H.B. 1551). (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1986
    - Arson (H.B. 100). (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Crime Victims Rights Act. (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Drivers Education Vehicles (H.B. 200). (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Emergency Warning Lights (H.B. 202). (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Fees for Garnishee-Employers (H.B. 201). (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous Notes. (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Relief of John C. Sample (H.B. 103). (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Town Council Appointments (H.B. 67). (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1987
    - Change in Assessment Period (H.B. 1221). (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Conservation Easement Act. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Limits on Crab Dredges (H.B. 927). (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous. (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Patron Report. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Painter Town Charter (H.B. 926). (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Real Estate Transfer Tax (S.B. 547). (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Taking Crabs on Sunday (H.B. 1058). (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1988
    - Catching Crabs for Household Use (H.B. 324). (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Non-Tidal Wetlands (H.B. 1037). (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
    - Oyster Tax (H.B. 706). (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Pound Nets Study. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1990
    - Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel - Second Parallel Bridge Tunnel. (Box 4, Folder 10-11)
    - Crab Traps (H.B. 477). (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Insurance Coverage - Mental Disabilities Task Force (H.J.R. 42). (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Storage Batteries (H.B. 476). (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Voluntary Annexation Agreements (H.B. 206). (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 1991
    - Accomack County School Board Salaries (H.B. 1395). (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Board of Zoning Appeals (H.B. 1396). (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Chesapeake Bay Preservation Act (H.B. 1664). (Box 5, Folder 1-3)
    - Child Labor Laws Subcommittee. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Chincoteague Town Charter (H.B. 1256). (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Crab Scrapes (H.B. 1419). (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Enhanced (E-911) Emergency Telephone System Tax (H.B. 1397). (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Firearms on School Property (H.B. 1537). (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Fishing Net Distances (H.B. 1463). (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Library Books. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Light House Ministries Tax Exemption (H.B. 1222). (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Lions Club Sales Tax Exemption (H.B. 1255). (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Non-Resident Harvester Fee (H.B. 1372). (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Peeler Pots (H.B 1418). (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Redistricting. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Redistricting. (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
    - School Bus Drivers Age Study (H.J.R. 320). (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Sweet Potato Board (H.B. 1269). (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 1992
    - Aquaculture Development (H.B. 530). (Box 6, Folder 8-9)
    - Comprehensive Services for At-Risk Youth and Families Act (H.B. 935). (Box 6, Folder 10-11)
    - Comprehensive Services for At-Risk Youth and Families Act (H.B. 935). (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Crab Pots (H.B. 529). (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Deer Rifle Hunting - Northampton County (H.B. 457). (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - East, Billy (H.B. 330). (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Eel Pots (H.B. 863). (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hydraulic Crab Scraping. (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Oyster Measurers (H.B. 895). (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - 1993
    - Business Classification for Personal Property. (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Child Support Disclosure (H.B. 2046). (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Coleman Bridge (H.B. 1424). (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Family Court. (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Hydraulic Clam Dredges. (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Keller Town Charter. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Tangier Fire Equipment Inspection Exemption. (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Tangier Island Golf Carts (H.B. 1056). (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 1994
    - Agriculture Bonds (H.B. 610). (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Annual Budgets for School Purposes (H.B. 606). (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Conservation Stamp (H.B. 1329). (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Major Business Facility Job Tax Credit (H.B. 1407). (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Management of Ungranted Shores (H.B. 391). (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Menhaden Fishing (H.B. 206). (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Motor Fuel Tax Refunds (H.B. 894). (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Nutrient Management Training Program (H.B. 609). (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Payment of Taxes by Performance of Part-Time Work (H.B. 895). (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Reissue of Boat Decal (H.B. 904) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Spousal Support (H.B. 1323). (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Tangier Island (H.B. 346). (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Uniform Interstate Family Support Act (H.B. 1328). (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
    - Welfare Recipients' Income/Federal Housing Subsidies (H.J.R. 155). (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - West Mathews Community League Tax Exemption (H.B. 8). (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Wetlands/VMRC. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Workers' Comp/Medical Cost Containment Strategies (H.J.R. 156). (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Workers' Comp/Presumption (H.B. 896). (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - 1995
    - Colona, Steven. (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Dentist Licensure by Endorsement (H.B. 2195). (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Eastern Shore Food Bank Tax Exemption. (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Eastern Shore Rural Health System Tax Exemption. (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Expenses of Magistrates (H.B. 2197). (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Inventories of Ungranted Shores (H.B. 2193). (Box 8, Folder 21-23)
    - Inventories of Ungranted Shores (H.B. 2193). (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - Maintenance Dredging Permit Fees (H.B. 1679). (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Medallion II Program (H.B. 1407). (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - NASA 50th Anniversary - Wallops. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - SHARE Tax Exemption (H.B. 1599). (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Solid Waste Disposal (H.B. 2196). (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - 1996
    - ABC Mixers/Blue Crab Bay Co. (H.B. 1442). (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Accomack County School Renovations. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Accomack Trailers (H.B. 1447). (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Bad Actor" Law (H.J.R. 148). (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Channel Maintenance Dredging (H.J.R. 149). (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
    - Chesapeake Bay Local Assistance Department (H.B. 1445). (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Future Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services (H.J.R. 240). (Box 9, Folder 16-17)
    - Future Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services (H.J.R. 240). (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
    - Future Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services (H.J.R. 240) - Preliminary Recommendations. (Box 10, Folder 5-8)
    - Grain Discount Rates (H.B. 1443). (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - H2A Migrants (H.B. 1555). (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Hydraulic Dredges (H.B. 937). (Box 10, Folder 11-12)
    - Juvenile Community Crime Control (H.B. 384). (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Minnows. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Report New Hire to the Virginia Employment Commission (H.B. 385). (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Security for Public Deposits Act (H.B. 386). (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Submerged Aquatic Vegetation. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - 1997
    - Cigarette Tax (H.B. 2204). (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Hemp Study (H.J.R. 656). (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
    - Judicial Review Commission. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Mathews County School Board Salaries. (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Personal Property Classification (H.B. 2203). (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Supplemental Environmental Projects (H.B. 2110). (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Tampering With Electric Meter (H.B. 2207). (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - VMRC Appointee. (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - 1998
    - Appropriations Committee - Capital Outlay. (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Appropriations Committee - Higher Education. (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Appropriations Committee - Natural Resources. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Appropriations Committee - Organizational Meeting. (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Bills. (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Bridge Exemptions (H.B. 996). (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel - Wardrup (H.B. 692). (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Child Labor Laws Exemptions (H.B. 1254). (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Country of Origin Labeling (H.B. 655). (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Food in Peeler Crab Pots (H.B. 656). (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Francis Makemie Society Tax Exemption. (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Future Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services - Medicaid Work Group (H.J.R. 225). (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
    - Future Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services - (H.J.R. 225), 16 December 1999. (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
    - Future Delivery of Publicly Funded Mental Health, Mental Retardation and Substance Abuse Services - (H.J.R. 225), 11 January 2000. (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 18 May 1998. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 22 June 1998. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 27 July 1998. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 21 September 1998. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 23 November 1998. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - House Appropriations Committee Regional Tour, 18-19 October 1998. (Box 13, Folder 2-4)
    - House Appropriations, House Finance, Senate Finance Committees Joint Meeting, 17 August 1998. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Human Rights Work Group (H.J.R. 225). (Box 13, Folder 6-9)
    - Mathews Court House Players Tax Exemption. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Motor Vehicles Sales and Use Tax Exemption (H.B. 27). (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Northampton County - Indexing by Tax Map Reference Number. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Oyster Inspection Tax (H.B. 992). (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Real Estate Board - Exemption from Licensure (H.B. 994). (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Tangier Fishing Gear and License Exemption (H.B. 993). (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Wetlands Mitigation Banking (S.B. 582). (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - 1999
    - Appropriations Committee - Organizational Meeting. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Arrest Without Warrant. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Farmers' Market Study (H.J.R. 506). (Box 14, Folder 4-6)
    - Francis Makemie Society Tax Exemption (H.B. 1684). (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 28 June 1999. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 22 November 1999. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - House Appropriations Committee - Health and Human Resources Subcommittee. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Lottery Revenue (H.B. 2513). (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Smoking in Ambulance (H.B. 2512). (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 2000
    - Appropriations Committee - Comprehensive Services Act. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Appropriations Committee - Organizational Meeting. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Appropriations Committee - Technology Work Group. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Chesapeake and Its Tributaries Committee. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Cook, Ann E. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Cotton Board (H.B. 1037). (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Dentistry in Underserved Areas. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Department for Rights of Virginians With Disabilities (H.B. 1304). (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Drinking Water Revolving Fund. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Forest Tax Credit (H.B. 1306). (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 19 June 2000. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 24 July 2000. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 16 October 2000. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 17 November 2000. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - House Appropriations, House Finance, and Senate Finance Committees Joint Meeting, 21 August 2000. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Marine Habitat and Waterways Improvement Fund (H.B. 1305). (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Trooper Troy D. Ashe Service Revolver (H.B. 183). (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Volunteer Fire Departments Tax Exemption. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - VRS Creditable Service (H.B. 184). (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Workers' Compensation for Illegal Aliens (H.B. 1036). (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - 2001
    - Accomack County - Manufactured Home Titles (H.B. 2029). (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Appropriations Committee - Staff, Calendars, etc. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Barrier Islands Tax Exemption (H.B. 2182). (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Crabbing Exemptions. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Exterior Illumination Regulation (H.B. 2026). (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Hands Across Mathews Tax Exemption (H.B. 2182). (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 18 June 2001. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 15 October 2001. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 16 November 2001. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - House Appropriations, House Finance, and Senate Finance Committees Joint Meeting, 20 August 2001. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Legislation. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Mathews County Land Conservancy Tax Exemption (H.B. 2182). (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Orbital Sciences Corporation Tax Exemption (H.B. 2414). (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Posession of Firearms by Felons (H.B. 2027). (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Redistricting. (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
    - Redistricting. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Town of Parksley/Chief of Police. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Treatment Options for Offenders Who Have Mental Illnesses or Substance Abuse Disorders (S.J.R. 440). (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
  - 2002
    - Agriculture Committee. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Appropriations Committee - Staff, Calendars, etc. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Arlington Foundation Tax Exemption (H.B. 727). (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Cape Charles - Golf Carts. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Cape Charles Town Charter. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel Transfer. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Disability Housing (H.J.R. 251). (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Exmore Town Charter (H.B. 612). (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - James Vincent Morgan Bridges (H.B. 614). (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Legal Services to Chaplains (H.B. 615). (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Public Safety, Militia, and Police. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Racing Commission (S.B. 638). (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Solid Waste Tipping Fee (S.B. 592). (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Standing Subcommittees. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Willis Wharf Village Trust Tax Exemption (H.B. 727). (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - 2003
    - Enterprise Zones (H.B. 1988). (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Fee on Vehicles Used in Harvesting (H.B. 1995). (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Fees for Solid Waste Disposal (H.B. 1992). (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Local Cigarette Tax (H.B. 2729). (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Parsons, Brian. (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Perkins Funding (H.J.R. 752). (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Regional Housing Authorities (H.B. 1989/1990). (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Regional Housing Authories - Section 8 (H.B. 1990). (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Transfer Fee on Real Estate Transactions (H.B. 2730). (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Virginia Board for People With Disabilities (H.B. 1987). (Box 17, Folder 29)
- Series II. Issue Files, 1978-2003., Extent: 45 boxes. (Box 18-62)
  The issue files contain material on a variety of matters of interest to Bloxom's constituents in the 100th District. There is correspondence between him and local citizens, government officials, groups, and organizations. A good deal of correspondence can be found in the "Miscellaneous" folders. The issue files also contain agendas, background information, brochures and pamphlets, budgets, clippings, grant applications memoranda, minutes, news releases, newsletters, notes, and reports. There is a large amount of information on blue crab protection, harvesting, and management, car tax legislation, the Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel, the Commerical Space Flight Authority and Mid-Atlantic Regional Spaceport on Wallops Island, dry fire hydrant systems, Eastern Shore Community College, Eastern Shore Railroad, the Eastern Shore Resource Conservation and Development Project, economic development, farmers' markets, fire companies and emergency medical services, fishing licensing, general obligation bonds, groundwater, Kiptopeke State Park, land conservation and use, lottery proceeds, migrant farmers, outdoor recreation, oysters, plasticulture, poultry waste, the proposed prison in Northampton County, state and federal retirees, school health, subaqueous minerals and materials, taxes, tributary nutrient reduction strategies, truck lengths and weights, unemployment trust fund, Virginia Port Authority and aid to local ports for various projects, wetlands, and workers' compensation. Arranged alphabetically.
  - A and N Electric Cooperative. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Abortion. (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Accomack County Airport. (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Accomack County Department of Social Services. (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Accomack County - School Health. (Box 18, Folder 5-10)
  - Accomack Northampton Advisory Council. (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
  - Accomack Northampton Planning District Commission. (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Accomack Northampton Planning District Commmission/Housing. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Accomack Northampton Planning District Commmission/Housing. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Acccomack - Peaker Plant. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Adult Protective Services. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Agriculture. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Appropriations. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Aquaculture. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Arabian Hill Horse Park. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Attorney General. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Auto Inspections. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Baylor Survey (Oysters). (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
  - Beaches, Islands, Marshes, and Woodlands. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Bell Atlantic/Right-of-Way Fee. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Bicycle Helmets. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Billboards. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Bingo. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Birding Festival. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Bonds. (Box 19, Folder 19-21)
  - Bonds. (Box 20, Folder 1-6)
  - Bottle Bill. (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - Bridge Tunnel. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Broiler Chicken Industry. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Caboose Bill. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Campaign Finance Reform. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Captain's Cove. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of Public Need (COPN) Program. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Chelation Therapy. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Chesapeake Bay Bridge Tunnel. (Box 20, Folder 16)